What's your take on Pakistan?
The economy is on the brink of collapse.
The source of money is drying up.
The world is very late in realising
how much of a threat it poses.
And there is no such thing as a good terrorist and a bad terrorist.
Kind of money the Americans have pumped into Pakistan is insane.
It's like the perfect storm that Pakistan is going through.
And we don't want the state to collapse
because we can't change the geography.
We can't change who enables.
You're basically saying it's unpredictable what will happen.
But it's likely that it will be a volatile situation.
It may break up for all we know.
The country may break up.
This just too much tension.